Jim C. Goldbloom GoldTechPro LLC

IT Consultant / Drupal Developer (Presently Employed)

jim@goldtechpro.com http://www.goldtechpro.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/jimgoldbloom

3810 Laramie Place Unit E Alexandria, VA 22309 (703) 258-5413

SUMMARY

Over 16 years experienced senior level IT professional skilled in back end development layers of the Internet web technology stack, specializing in open source technologies including LAMP and the Drupal based Content Management System (CMS) and Acquia Cloud. My roles include primary content provider, custom module developer and team leader for high traffic private sector and government projects. Excellent communication skills allow me to interface with stakeholders, either technical or lay oriented and via individual or group training, to accurately identify and meet the needs of the client and their end users. I established and maintain my own IT consulting firm.

TECHNOLOGIES & SKILLS

- * XHTML 1.0, XML/XSL 1.0, HTML 5, CSS 2/3, JavaScript/DHTML, Ajax, JSON
- * LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP) including XAMP/MAMP Pro for Windows/Mac
- * PHP 5 (Object Oriented Programming, class development)
- * MySQL 5 database, Oracle 11G database
- * Acquia PaaS, migration to and setup and optimization of the Acquia Cloud
- * JavaScript open source frameworks (¡Query and Agile Toolkit/MVC, MooTools, Script.aculo.us)
- * Drupal 6/7 Content Management System, custom theme, module and API development, Drush
- * CVS (SVN and GIT/GITHUB) repository staging, commit, clone, push and rollback
- * Social Networking rich web 2.0 mashups including Facebook, Twitter, ShareThis
- * SEO strategies, Google Custom Search API, Drupal/Apache Solr, Atomz PDF Search
- * Word Press, phpBB and vBulletin forum software, 123 FlashChat live chat Drupal integration
- * RSS news feed resource syndication (XML/RDF 1.0, RSS 2.0/Atom implementation)
- * Linux system administration including custom shell scripts, crontab, IPTables local firewall setup, daemon installation (RPM, YUM, direct binary source compiling x386 or x64)
- * VM Ware virtual server guest setup and host configuration
- * Komodo, Macromedia DreamWeaver MX Studio IDE, Aptana Stuido, Zend Studio, JIRA
- * Adobe Photoshop CS5 graphic format creation/editing tools
- * SpamAssassin, Procmail and virtual mail mapping/alias/DNS setup, SSH/FTP access

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Strayer University - Arlington Campus, Virginia

Graduated 2003

- * Computer Information Systems, Diploma in Web Development, 2001-2003
- * Accredited Diploma providing highly focused academic work in a specific technical area

Accolades: President's List Honoree GPA: 4.0

Jim C. Goldbloom (703) 258-5413

RELATED WORK EXPERIENCE

HireStrategy - Reston, Virginia

May 2012-Present

Drupal Developer (Consultant)

Contract: The College Board (12 months, extended to April 30th 2013)

Job Site: Reston, VA

http://www.collegeboard.org

* Member of the New Media/Site Optimization Team responsible for Drupal CMS customization and updates

- * Drupal theme implementation
- * Custom module development and third party open source integration
- * Port legacy Drupal 6 sites to version 7
- * Work closely with Business Analysts, design team and other stakeholdeers during all phases of development projects
- * Analyze requirements and provide scalable and maintainable technical design solutions
- * Provide necessary documentation and technical support for groups or individuals
- * Linux shell scripting tasks
- * PHP/MySQL and LAMP technology stack optimization and routine maintenance

Web Development Special Projects

- * Acquia PaaS Migration of 40+ Drupal sites to the Acquia Cloud in a high profile project for the organization. Created and executed a comprehensive migration plan which included Drupal and Acquia setup and optimization to ensure a smooth migration and future code deployment.
- * You Can Go Created a PHP CLI script run once daily via crontab to query the delta from a key database storing college information via a secure RESTFUL API and includes local, dev and prod configuration, a rebuild mode to resync lost data, syslog updating.
- * Drupal custom modules:
 - "Robots.TXT" -- allows a dev and prod version managed through the CMT.
 - "Varnish Cache Purge" Acquia utility to auto-purge Varnish cache on node CRUD
 - "QuickFinder" -- Integrates a specific API for searching college data into any Drupal site,
- * Domain Access module removal a key project involving 4 high profile sites in the organization (about, press, membership and socialmedia) that originally were part of a multisite
- * [Marketing] Landing Page (LP) New Drupal 7 site with integrated Omege 960 grid theme for creating template based landing pages linked from other CB sites for marketing purposes
- * Student Landing Page (SLP) Drupal 6 to 7 migration, Omega 960 grid theme and delta setup.
- * Student Search Services (SSS, SSD, CSS/FAP) Microsites added into SLP with custom templating and layout system using Omega, Context and Display Suite.

"Jim has now gained extensive experience with Acquia PaaS, migrating 40+ sites into the platform which now hosts all of our Drupal sites. The success of that migration can be solely attributed to Jim's diligent work and his ability to surmount obstacles through creative solutions." – Ian Mieville, Director of Content Management Systems, College Board

Navigation Arts - McLean, Virginia

June 2011-Dec 2011

Drupal Developer (Full time, In-House)

http://www.gpfi.org (IFC, Global Partnership for Financial Inclusion site)
http://www.smefinanceforum.org (IFC, Small and Medium Enterprises Finance Forum site)
http://www.nmwa.org (National Museum of Women in the Arts site)

Blog: http://blog.navigationarts.com/drupal-7-a-coming-of-age-story/ (Drupal 7: Coming of Age)

- * Drupal back end web development including application development, server configuration and Content Management System integration and customization
- * Translated design comps and wireframes into a system of flexible and reusable code templates while maintaining an extreme attention to detail for concurrent projects
- * Collaborated with team members to determine the best solution for client and user needs
- * Developed and delivered production-ready code and supporting documentation in a timely manner with high quality results
- * Communicated and collaborated with the project manager, engineers, designers, and site authors in all stages of production
- * Delivered on multiple projects at once while adequately managing individual schedules and work quality
- * Drupal, LAMP support and technical liaison for all Navigation Arts departments

Web Development Special Projects

- * Assisted IFC with security remediation for two major sites to pass a comprehensive security scan required by the client's SOC/NOC
- * Worked with Quality Assurance Test Architect to modernize and standardize the Drupal CMS Specifications template to streamline work flow and optimize the QA testing procedure within the Tracker application

Related Training

* Washington D.C. Drupal Intermediate Training – July 21, 2011 Phase 2 Technologies, Alexandria Virginia

"As a project manager, I relied on his time estimates as well as his meticulous attention to detail. His delivery was consistent and his work product was outstanding, much to the delight of his entire team." – Michael Heckman, PM

Jim C. Goldbloom (703) 258-5413

Ace Info Solutions, Inc. - McLean, Virginia

May 2004-Jan 2011

Web Developer / LAMP / Drupal Developer

Contract: Minority Business Development Agency (MBDA) Job Site: Department of Commerce, Washington, D.C.

http://www.mbda.gov (web portal)

http://www.medweek.gov (third party hosted)

http://partnernet.mbda.gov (social networking within the agency and it's Funded Centers)

- * Senior Web Developer for all agency web sites including site design, application development, server configuration and Content Management System integration
- * Team Leader overseeing projects involving Junior Web Developer, Content Manager, Network Engineer and associated stakeholders
- * LAMP/VM Ware based web server administration and security protocols
- * Work closely with Business Analysts and other developers and stakeholders within the agency's operating business units
- * Analyze requirements and provide recommended technical design solutions that are efficient, scalable and maintainable via the SDLC and in-house version control system
- * Provide training, documentation and technical support for individual or group presentation

Web Development Special Projects

- * Reboot of the agency web portal (2010) full integration of Drupal CMS including custom themes and module development into legacy infrastructure (PHP/MySQL, CF/Oracle)
- * Introduced social networking and Rich Web 2.0 mashups to the web technology stack for all web sites including RSS, Facebook, Twitter, Share This, You Tube and Word Press
- * LDAP authentication and employee directory module for Drupal
- * Linux security hardening project resolved critical security issues all MBDA Linux servers
- * Implemented the agency's third party hosted MED Week web site managed remote configuration and security hardening of the LAMP setup and Drupal configuration
- * Design, build and implementation of PartnerNet web site for MBDA staff and funded centers with emphasis on social networking mashups and Communities of Practice
- * Event Registration Application a calendar driven, PHP/CF/Oracle web application with checkin, checkout interface and reports generation engine
- * Media Gallery an audio/video/document repository web application with advanced gallery features integrated with RSS syndication and iTunes Podcasting
- * MBDA Community Exchange a seamless integration of the popular open source phpBB forum software with bridged user database
- * Dynamic custom content approval system (prior to reboot) time sensitive content submissions follow multi-level approval/rejection process flow, incoming queues, E-Mail notifications and logging
- * Custom search engine web application and template system with search index generated via crontab spider crawl and ranked/paginated results including optional topic highlighting
- * Fully integrated custom PHP error handler with detailed error logging for administrators and E-Mail reporting tools and sensible controls to prevent looping
- * Searchable and interactive knowledge base (Frequently Asked Questions) a user submitted/staff approved Q&A and polls web application
- * Contract Tracking Database a custom built staff accessible web application written in PHP/MySQL storing client supplied contracting opportunities following Hurricane Katrina in 2004

Jim C. Goldbloom (703) 258-5413

Computer-Help, Inc. / Unisys - Crystal City, Virginia

Sep 2002-Nov 2002

Help Desk Technician, Junior Web Developer Contract: 90 days

http://gsaauctions.gov (General Services Administration web site)

- * Team Lead, Help Desk Established new Help Desk organizational infrastructure
- * Interview, hire and train initial Help Desk team members
- * Design Web based solutions as applicable and maintain content at gsaauctions.gov

Web Development Special Projects

* Designed and implemented a custom trouble ticket tracking web application in PHP/MySQL

NTT/Verio, Inc. - Springfield, Virginia

Oct 1997-Feb 2002

Customer Engineer (CE) Level 2 - Quality Assurance

- * Sole Quality Assurance for CE Technical Support and all national on-call escalations.
- * Level 2 Technical Support, selected to the first national Network Operations Center (NOC) oncall team uniquely identified as "CE Technical Support".
- * Level 1 client side Personal Web page setup, E-Mail, DNS and related zone setup.
- * Primary technical liaison between sales and network engineering and the national Customer Service Organization (CSO) for all support and broadband WAN installations.

Monumental Network Systems - Chantilly, Virginia

Nov 1996-Oct 1997

Sales Engineer, Technical Support (Company was acquired by Verio, Inc. in 1997)

- * Develop intranet Web site to serve as repository for support related tutorial files.
- * Technical contact and advisor for sales representatives and agents, pre-contract.
- * Dialup and dedicated access daytime technical support (PPP, ISDN, DS1, DS3).
- * On-call support within Network Operations Center (NOC duty)

Web Development Special Projects

- * Designed intranet Web site to document escalation procedures adopted nationally.
- * Developed intranet Web site to configure and quality check all access WAN related DNS.

Groups and Organizations

Member and presenter, Drupal4Gov – Drupal Project Planning, i.e. documentation and discussion to help agencies new to Drupal get started. http://drupal4gov.betaspaces.com/members

Unique Recognition

"Above and Beyond Award" (Indyne, 2004) engraved:

"We hereby express our sincere appreciation to Jim Goldbloom in grateful recognition of your outstanding performance, team spirit, and commitment to excellence."

ADDITIONAL REFERENCES

"I consider Jim to be a top notch Drupal module developer, who works within the API and follows community best practices. He has successfully developed numerous modules to meet business requirements and has repaired dozens of modules with sometimes incredibly obscure bugs. During his tenure, we saw a dramatic improvement in the performance and stability of the sites he worked on." – John Warren, Lead Drupal Engineer, College Board

"Jim maintained a positive attitude in the face of challenging demands from the client. Jim consistently put in the extra time and effort needed to achieve excellent results. In short, he is a consummate development professional with whom I would gladly work again." – Michael Heckman, Project Manager, Navigation Arts

"Jim is always there and consistently exceeds our expectations with his designs and innovative solutions. He was instrumental on many occasions for publishing our MedWeek wite leading to increased participants at that event. He is very reliable and does not hesitate to devote extra time and resources to ensure we are the best in class." – Yolanda Whitley, Chief Information Officer, Minority Business Development Agency

"As a Director of Verio Customer Engineering, I watched Jim play a leadership role in writing system tools and scripts for the department. As a programmer, he is very thorough in his documentation and his work products." - Andy Peterson, NTT/Verio, Inc.

"Jim distinguished himself among his peers by developing tools and processes that consistently exceeded the expectations of my self and of my directors. Solutions that he created were imaginative and efficient and they positively impacted our internal operations and our service to our customers." - Craig Harlow, Manager, Customer Engineer, NTT/Verio, Inc.

Additional letters of recommendation are available upon request or at GoldTechPro.com